let's say that a contract has some state
假设合同具有一些状态变量和功能，
variables and functions in solidity you
have to declare whether a child contract
必须声明子合同，其他合同或帐户是否可以访问
other contracts or accounts have access
to these state variables and functions
在本视频中，我们将介绍这些状态变量和函数
in this video we're going to go over the
four key words that determine the
决定状态变量可见性的四个关键词
visibility of state variables and
functions these key words are private
这些关键词的功能是私人的，内部的，公共的，外部的，国家的
internal public and external a state
variable or a function declared private
变量或声明为私有的函数意味着只能在内部访问
means that it is only accessible inside
the contract that defines it for example
定义它的合同，例如，如果合同具有私有状态
if a contract has a private state
variable and another contract and heads
变量和另一个合同，然后从该计划合同中选择，然后是孩子
from that plan contract then the child
contract does not have access to that
合同无权访问在
private state variable defined in the
pair contract when a state variable or
当状态变量或函数声明为内部变量时，配对合同然后
function is declared as internal then
that means that it is accessible inside
这意味着它可以在合同本身和子合同中访问
a contract itself and the child contract
but it is not accessible by other
但是其他合同无法访问它，并且在公共状态下也无法访问
contracts and accounts a public state
variable or a function is accessible by
变量或函数可以通过任何合同和任何帐户访问，并且如果
any contract and any account and if a
contract has an external function then
合同有一个外部功能，那么该功能只能由
that function can only be called by
other contracts and accounts and an
其他合同和账户，并且外部状态变量不存在
external state variable does not exist
since it doesn't make sense to have a
因为拥有仅存储数据的状态变量是没有意义的
state variable that stores data only be
accessible by other contracts and
现在可以通过其他合同和帐户访问足够多的数据了
accounts that's enough top for now let's
see some code here we have a private
在这里看到一些代码，我们有一个名为私人电话的私人功能，
function named private phone that
returns the same public function called
返回相同的公共函数，而私钥使它
and the private key word makes this
function only accessible inside this
功能仅在此合同内以及如果您部署此合同时可访问
contract and if you deploy this contract
you'll notice that you cannot call the
您会注意到您无法调用私有函数，但这是完美的
private function but it is perfectly
fine to have a public function and
拥有公共功能很好，并且在内部调用私有功能，但是
inside it call the private function but
a child contract cannot call this
子合同无法调用此函数，因为关键字private
function since the keyword private makes
this function
该功能在合同内可见
visible inside the contract that it is
defined in an internal function can be
可以在内部函数中调用在内部函数中定义的
called inside the contract that it is
defined in and also inside the child
在儿童文化中以及在儿童文化中进行定义，我们将通过以下方式对此进行测试
culture and we're gonna test this out by
creating a public function inside the
在基本合同和子合同中创建公共职能
base contract and the child contract
inside the function we're gonna call the
在函数内部，我们将调用内部函数重新编译和部署
internal function recompile and deploy
both the base and the child contract and
基本合同和子合同都可以，您可以在此处看到两个合同都是
you can see here that both contracts are
able to call the internal function
能够将内部函数称为公共函数
inside the public function a public
function can be called inside this
该功能可以在子合同中由其他合同调用
contract by child contracts by other
contracts and accounts an external
合同和账目外部功能只能由其他人调用
function can only be called by other
contracts and accounts so that means you
合约和帐户，因此您无法在另一个内部调用此函数
cannot call this function inside another
function here I've created a public
我在这里创建了一个公共函数来调用外部函数
function that calls the external
function inside it this code will not
里面的函数，因为外部函数是
compile since the external function is
not accessible inside the contract it
在合同内部无法访问，只能从其他合同中调用
can only be called from other contracts
and accounts and the same visibility's
和帐户，并且状态变量的可见性相同，但
applied to state variables except the
keyword external the state variable
关键字external不能将状态变量声明为external。
cannot be declared as external doing so
you can see here that the code does not
您可以在此处看到，尽管私有状态变量也无法编译代码
compile although private state variables
are only accessible inside the contract
只能在合同内访问，这并不意味着您应该存储
this does not mean that you should store
sensitive information inside it since
内部的敏感信息，因为区块链上的所有内容都是可见的
everything on the blockchain is visible
to everyone it is not difficult to find
对于每个人来说，找到存储在私有状态中的值并不难
the value stored in a private state
variable and the same caution should be
变量，对内部状态变量应采取与以下相同的注意事项：
applied to internal state variables as
well
出色地
in this video we went over the four
在本视频中，我们介绍了状态变量和
visibilities that our state variable and
functions can have private means it is
函数可以具有私有手段，它仅在合同内部可见
only visible inside the contract
internal means it is only visible inside
内部意味着它仅在合同内部和子合同公共内部可见
the contract and child contract public
means it is visible to the contract
表示合同的合同子合同可见
child contract of the contracts and
accounts external means it is visible to
外部帐户表示其他合同和帐户可见
other contracts and accounts and not
visible inside the contract and don'ts
在合同内可见，在私人和内部不存在或没有秘密
or secrets inside private and internal
state variables if you have any
状态变量，如果您有任何疑问，请把它们放在
questions please put them in the
comments below thanks for watching and
以下评论感谢您的收看，下回见
I'll see you next time